Rahul Hareendran

Bangalore, India | LinkedIn | +91 968 6699 669 | rahulmax@gmail.com | rahulmax.com

SUMMARY

Product designer and User Experience Architect with 14+ years' experience. Proven experience building UX design processes, design teams and design systems to create impactful products, for global banks and Fintech companies such as MetroBank UK, ila Bank (Bahrain) and ICICI Bank (India). Follows user centered design and lean UX practices, focused on business goals and user needs. Read more about the design process here.

WORK EXPERIENCE

MetroBank UK London, United Kingdom

Principal Product Design Consultant

July 2021 → Present

- Designed UX for commercial banking, reducing call volumes by 17%, rectifying major customer pain points by conducting research, redesigning key user journeys and information architecture
- Improved business origination and customer onboarding decline rate by 21% by enhancing onboarding user experience
- Created seamless and delightful user experiences for Metrobank's banking products catering to 2.6 million+ customers

ila Bank Manama, Bahrain

Principal User Experience Architect

December 2019 → June 2021

- Established and guided a design team of 8+ designers, managed 5+ design agencies and creators, and implemented UX design process for ila Bank's digital banking platform serving 120,000+ customers in Bahrain
- Created delightful experiences that won 10+ awards including <u>Global Finance Middle East's Best UX Design</u>, <u>Seamless'</u>
 Best Banking Experience award, <u>Transform MEA award</u>, and <u>Gartner Eye on Innovation Award</u>
- Implemented UX for a fully digital onboarding in less than 5 minutes, improved from Backbase MVP's >11 minutes
- Designed user experience for personal savings products which increased average funding per customer by 7%
- Created UX and UI for fixed term deposits which accrued USD 15 million+ in deposits within the first month of launch

DH Anticounterfeit Halmstad, Sweden

User Experience Architect

May $2018 \rightarrow December 2019$

- Created UX for CaseMate, for brand protection used by 60+ clients such as Daimler, Volkswagen, PVH, Sony & Superdry
- Built the insights engine and increased website take-downs by 40% and marketplace listing take-downs by 34%
- Developed the UI, Design System and component library for Casemate

ScreenRoot / SynerLabs / Fuzzie, Singapore

Banking & Fintech Consulting, India

Product Design Specialist

May 2017 - April 2018

- Built UX and UI for ICICI Bank's banking app. Improved the app store ratings to 4.6/5 from 4.1/5 in 3 months of launch
- Overhauled UX and UI for HDFC Bank car loans, decreasing the drop-off / abandonment rate by 9%
- Conceived a delightful UX/UI for Fuzzie, a gifting and rewards app catering to 20,000+ users

BigBinary Miami, FL / Remote

Lead Product Designer

August 2014 \rightarrow May 2017

- Implemented UX, UI for the compliance manager solution, AAPC Healthicity involving 10 key tools for compliance
- Designed UI and Front-end for the Real estate agent platform, AgentInbox (Acquired by MLS Aligned) used by 20,000+ agents to connect with users and arrange hassle-free property viewing
- Implemented UI and Front-end for UL Solutions' Markshub, UL Go and UL Verify, servicing more than 1,500 standards
- Built UX, UI and Front-end for smart car tracking app, AutoBrain to help make driving safer for 40,000+ customers

Bang the Table (Granicus)

Melbourne, Australia / Bangalore, India / Remote

Lead UI/UX & Front-end Designer

May $2010 \rightarrow July 2014$

- Designed UX, UI for EngagementHQ which increased engagement by 28% across tools like Q&A, forums and surveys
- Implemented a front-end branding framework, which enabled quick theme turnaround time from 8 weeks to 2 weeks
- Designed experiences for 12 major EHQ re-brands for State Governments in Australia for mass community engagement
- Revamped EngagementHQ platform for accessibility and received WCAG 2.1 AA certification from Vision Australia

Beehively Ahmedabad, India

UI/UX Designer

August 2008 \rightarrow April 2010

- Designed UI/UX and Front-end framework for school management software, Beehively connecting parents, teachers and students of 100+ public and private schools in the US
- Built UI and Front-end for Insightify, a survey designer tool, which enables launching a survey in under 5 minutes

SKILLS

Hard Skills

Product Design, User Experience Research, Product Strategy, Competitor Analysis, Strategic planning, Stakeholder Interviews, User Interface Design, Interaction Design, Information Architecture, Design Systems Management, Wireframing, Rapid Prototyping, Usability Testing, A/B Testing, User Interviews, Thematic Analysis, User Journey Mapping, Heuristic Analysis, Contextual Inquiries, Analytics Review, Agile Methodologies, Workshops

Tech Skills

Figma, Sketch, Adobe XD, Miro, Invision, Maze, Google Analytics, PowerBI, Lookback, UserTesting, Hotjar, Clicktale, UXCam

EDUCATION

Government Engineering College, Thrissur

Thrissur, India

Btech in Computer Science & Engineering

Specialization in Human Computer Interaction, UC San Diego

Coursera HCI